Jarod Romankiw

Strategy & Transformation manager with experience in strategy development, business transformation, earned value, program management. Problem solver with technical background in aerospace engineering and a passion for bringing creative and unique data visualization to strategic assessments.

Experience

Raytheon

Manager, Strategy & Transformation (2022 - Present)

Develop strategic assessments and data driven market research in partnership with company executives to drive actionable results and meaningful impacts to our organization. Strategic Assessments Include:

Alternate Site Strategy

RTX Business Realignment (4:3 Business Unit Consolidation) Competitive Benchmarking

Strategy Studies

Sr. Analyst, Engineering Business (2022 - 2023)

Control Account Manager (CAM), supported creation of Latest Revised Estimates (LRE) and Estimates at Complete (EAC). Regularly used Earned Value Management System (EVMS) techniques in conjunction with Microsoft Excel / Project.

Design Engineer II (2022 - 2023)

Designed and drafted detailed part and assembly drawings using PTC Creo, GD&T and DFMA techniques. Created Preliminary Design Review (PDR) and Mechanical Interconnects Diagrams. Engineering released new parts/drawings in PDM.

Pratt & Whitney

Design Engineer (2019 Intern)

Redesigned parts using structural, aerodynamic and thermal analysis on the commercial operating engine fleet to improve safety and reliability of components with the Siemens NX CAD platform.

Gulfstream Aerospace Corporation

Engineer (2018 Intern)

Proactively gathered in-flight data from G650/G650ER aircraft fleet, analyzed aircraft performance and developed predictive maintenance algorithms in MATLAB.

Carling Technologies

Design + Software Engineer (2016 - 2017 Intern)

Created a new JavaScript system to handle sales inquiries for various product lines and developed VBA driven Excel tools to track and organize part numbers.

Skills

Data Visualization Analytical Modeling

Primary and Secondary Research

Education

Worcester Polytechnic Institute

Master of Science, Mechanical Engineering Bachelor of Science, Aerospace Engineering